Hey
hey everyone welcome to another wasabi
today we are talking about Liu picks
low-latency anonymous communication
system with bi-directional third party
sender and receiver anonymity we're
lucky to have Ania poto suka join us
today one of the author's the primary
author of the paper and I did not
unfortunately write the names of all of
the authors so I'll just say them here
but of course you can find the names and
the PDF and all of that in our github
official wasabi research club github so
Jamie Hayes Tariq Kalani and sebastian
miser as well as george day's us i
should i messed up the names there but
okay so there's the there's the paper
and below is the link this is from 2017
i believe all right
just to recap of where we are what we've
been doing we talked about principles in
privacy in the beginning of march as
well as coin joint sodoku then we did
Boltzmann and last week we had probably
one of the most interesting discussions
that unfortunately i didn't attend but
it was for sure one of the best ones to
listen to you again on the topic of why
I am NOT an entropy and then of course
at the end of this meeting we'll decide
what we'll do next week and you can find
all of that at the link right right
below so what did we talk about last
week just reminder we talked about
entropy and privacy when we think about
privacy is it's not obvious to us how to
consider the strength of a particular to
of privacy when we look at encryption
and cryptography specifically it's easy
to think of cryptography in terms of
bits of strength and in terms of entropy
you can take ciphertext and you can take
plaintext and even compared how much
information can you get from the
ciphertext that will help you get back
to the plaintext but unfortunately there
are systems
example like tour where you can't easily
quantify how entropy matches the the
privacy and said you have to do that you
have to use metrics like the anonymity
set so we talked about this disparity
and there was a very interesting
conversation that you can look into so
just a brief reminder for anyone who
doesn't remember what tor is doing what
tor does is a bunch of participants work
together they're the the first
participant wealth will essentially look
at the network find a bunch of
essentially relays and encrypt data
against a bunch of relays so that the
data is like an onion that is being
unwrapped as it is moving across the
network and finally when it's on grab at
the very end it reaches for example some
website or server or potentially another
user
here's a nice so tour we can look at
tour like this so on the Left we have
the client node in red tour has entry
points entry knows followed by middle
relay nodes that pass messages and
decrypt and continue to pass messages
and finally exit relay notes that then
connect to the server so that's the
basic idea of what tor is doing and we
talked about well how we perceive tor so
when we think about what tor really is
we think of it as just this big black
box where information is being passed
along and all you see it's sort of in a
perfect world is users either getting
information from tor or receiving
information from tor and you don't know
who is where and that's the perfect
world as you wouldn't know but of course
we talked about problems so for example
with tor the problem is that if in this
case only one individual is currently
using the tor network that it's quite
obvious even though we can't see where
the you know the necessarily
encrypted information what we can see
that this websites being accessed via
tor in this purple individual is
accessing tor so we can we can deduce
from there that the two are connected
and likewise if we have individuals that
are behaving in a certain way for
example in english-speaking versus
Hungarian speaking users we can narrow
down one user over another because we
can observe common traits so again if a
Hungarian IP address is accessing tor
and there's a Hungarian website that's
getting a tour request then we can we
can make the conclusion that those two
are probably linked so loop X is
essentially remix reinventing the mix
Network so look me at that problem and
trying to figure out how we're gonna
overcome those obstacles so let's go
over the assumptions that loop fix is is
prepared to deal with also called a
threat model so the first thing is the
global pass of an adversary who's able
to observe the whole network and all
traffic between users and providers
providers and mixers mixers and other
mixers and is able to launch Network
attacks so people often say that tor is
not secure against such an adversary a
global passive adversary because of the
things that I just described in the
previous slide furthermore the adversary
can observe all the internal state of
corrupted or malicious mix relays and
the adversary can further reject delay
or remove messages being passed between
mix nodes and lastly the adversary can
participate and then make network as a
compromised user however the adversary
is not expected to be able to civil
attack the network which means on the
adversary is still a small percentage of
malicious users on the network and not
an overwhelming majority and I hope I
got these rights these are quite
important so if I got these wrong and I
can jump in and let me know otherwise
all sort of on here ok ok so perfect so
I'm going to introduce the
infrastructure and just really a the
very highest level explain how I
understood bluemix and then we can talk
about details and of course we can ask
and the a thousand quest
afterwards so there are users
these are senders and receivers there
are mixed servers that are partitioned
in strata which I'm going to explain in
the next slide and there are providers
and the providers are and I'll talk
about the providers as well in the next
slide so let's start with users so users
are both receivers and senders a user
could be a sender only or receiver only
or both so I'm just putting users and
receivers on the left hand on the right
but you can see that the red user can
exist on both the left and the right
then there are providers now providers
are if I understand correctly from the
paper they're analogous to like VPN
service providers providers are trusted
by the users and the yeast establish a a
like a connection with the provider like
it's invocation with the provider such a
way that maybe the user even pays the
provider for the service and so the
providers are analogous to DPS but
they're also analogous in the entry and
exit points of the Tor network so the
best analogy here of what providers are
and so here I've listed a bunch of
providers there can be as many as you
would like I'm just making it simple for
this image and next we have mixers and
here I've noted them as little onions
because they are in fact Onion Routing
they are passing information and mixing
them in a class it makes me mad but the
important thing to understand with these
mixers these mixing services is that
they exist in the strata so for the sake
of simplicity I'm just going to assume
that there are only exactly three strata
namely orange yellow and green and it
doesn't matter how many servers are in
each strata but what's important is that
that the providers always relay
information through each strata
sequentially so through the they'll pick
a random server for example through in
each strata and in this case it'll
always be a path of three servers from
provider to provider but it obviously
it's different in the actual
implementation
and so when we look at how the behavior
exists in this setup if I user wanted to
send a message to someone else like this
well then the user would would ping the
provider and the provider would route to
the other provider for example that that
would then relay it to the recipient
user so so far everything here appears
to be very very similar to the Tor
network it doesn't seem like there's
anything I've been taking so we're going
to get to to what how this is different
in just the next slide here important
thing is that a provider will you know
if Fred wants to send a long message to
yellow that message will be broken down
into packets and each packet will have
its own its own pathway even if red and
yellow have messages only between each
other each message will go through a
different routing a different words for
every packet this is already different
than torrent or we have these circuits
this is like a circuit analogous to
circuited tor and these circuits stay
for the duration that that were
interacting with a server and then only
if you manually kill that circuit and
create a new one that doesn't do this
change well in this model on that the
circuits are constantly being changed
between every packet I saw so that there
are some examples great
so providers are analogous to VPN
services as I described before mixed
servers are split into a fixed number of
strata messages always traverse through
each strata at one mix node and then
consecutive messages pick new random
paths even though they might go to the
same place
so these are some of the differences
that we might see between tour and loop
X now the most important idea oh yes and
I should have explained the goals more
clearly maybe this slide should have
been earlier but
the goal is sender receiver third party
on link ability so the idea is that a
global passive adversary cannot link up
a sender to a particular receiver
meaning that a global passive adversary
can't tell if sender one is linked to
receiver one or sender one is linked to
receiver two or if senator two is linked
to receiver one and and and etc etc the
next two are quite interesting so sender
online and observability means that a
global passive adversary cannot even
tell if a sender is sending something or
nothing at all and we're gonna see how
this is a treat in just a moment and
receiver on observability is when the
goal pass adversary cannot tell if the
message is intended for receiver or for
nobody at all and the way this is
achieved is through something called the
loops so it's called Lubich speak of it
centers around the city above the loop
and what is a loop a loop as a provider
sending a message to themselves as
though it's a legitimate message from a
potential user but it's actually not a
legitimate message it's no message at
all and so providers are doing these
loops all the time and different
providers are doing loops concurrently
with other providers and so what you
have is you have this these these decoys
that are constantly permeating the
traffic making it very hard to tell what
is a real intended message and what is a
decoy entirely so the decoy messages are
constantly being sent the decode
messages are purposefully constructed to
fit a plus on point process which
creates a random distribution of
messages sent across the network so the
clever thing here oh this will explain
number three the clever thing here is
that the providers are essentially
making a queue of messages that they're
going to be relayed into the network and
they have the sort of random timing of
the queue of next messages when a user
wants to send a legitimate message they
simply replace their message with
another message in the queue or simply
queue up their message it will you of a
decoy message and what that does is it
means that any individual message is is
not tampering with
the randomness of the traffic analysis
the traffic on the network always
appears random and it's unclear if any
particular message is important or if
it's a decoy entirely so essentially
what we have is a bunch of providers
sending messages to themselves in a
circle goes like this and yeah this
constant traffic that's happening and as
soon as a user want to send a message to
another user that is the that is
replacing a decoy message and traversing
the network just like this and there's
some more and nuance in terms of how a
user actually receives the message from
the provider and a lot of different
stuff there to guarantee that the user
the user does not reveal if they are in
fact receiving legitimate information
but I've left that out for simplicity
and for time so I think that I hope that
is pretty good like like you know a 10
kilometer high-level overview of what
the purpose of loop X is and how it
achieves its goal but you know in
summary by having a bunch of decoy
messages that are permitting this mimics
network we can avoid the traffic
analysis that makes tor less secure so
at this point we're gonna introduce or
we're gonna open it up for questions and
we're gonna let any I explain exactly
what I said wrong or sort of explain
what I left out so yeah that's pretty
much it
okay so maybe I'm gonna quickly jump in
I actually loved your presentation I
think it's amazing that you managed to
explain so well in such a short time
period I'm very very impressed I
actually have to like major comments one
is about the loop packets the loop
messages here there's a little nuance
here it's not only just providers
sending those loop messages it's
actually also the client sending the
loop messages and the mixes are sending
loop messages and now way this is done
the clients are sending groups to
themselves from time to time this is
completely independent process from
the normal messages at all and they do
it because they want to generate
two-sided cover traffic so they want to
obfuscate both the sending pattern and
they're receiving pattern the other
reason why clients are sending the loop
messages is for example because they
would like to take measurements of the
network so see whether the network is
congested or not or whether there are
any malicious mixes why the mixes are
sending group messages to themselves is
much more tricky it's to prevent active
attacks so what might happen is that if
you had an adversary who is able to
control the network traffic he can
actively attack a selected mix by
dropping the traffic which is flowing
towards this makes and letting only some
selected packets to go through and
because of that if he would block all
the other traffic and just let a couple
of packets go through this makes he
would be able to further trace where
this mix is forwarding those packets so
this is one small correction like you
explained the loops very very well it's
just it's not only the provider sending
them but also the users and the mixes
and one thing which I I would actually
add to this presentation which I think
is very important for loop agent for
mixed networks is that mixed networks
perform the mixing of the packets so
like reordering of the packets instead
of forwarding the packets at the first
in first out order like normal servers
once they receive packets they followed
them in the same order the mix is mixing
so reordering the packets what this
allows to achieve is to break the timing
correlation in tor you don't have it so
if you would put a global passive
adversary and let him look at the entire
Tor network what the adversary would be
able to do is to correlate every single
packet based on that timing so he would
see one packet coming into the Tor relay
and he would know that this will be the
first packet leaving the mix note a
reordering to break this timing
correlation but what is important
because of various designs
surgeons in loop X the latency
associated with this mixing which we
introduced is very small so comparing
tutorial loop X does not introduce much
high latencies then you would have int
order but it gives you a better security
to do this mixing and these are like my
two main comments actually about that
and it thank you so much for occur to me
and adding those comments can I ask you
to clarify as well about the
relationship between users and their
providers trust is there yes so actually
in the paper we stated that the
providers are honest but curious so
they're a bit like semi trusted so what
this means is that the providers act in
an honest way which means they do
exactly what they are supposed to do the
only thing which we say about the
providers is that they might somehow
cooperate with the adversary but by for
example telling him what they observed
so what the provider can try to tell the
adversary is oh I see Alice just sent 20
messages into the network or I see Bob
receiving 10 messages from the network
however the sending and receiving
patterns of both Alice and Bob are still
secured by those who look packets
because all the packets sent into the
mix network are end-to-end
Onion encrypted did this means that the
provider sees only some encrypted packet
which might be either a real message or
a look message and the same for the
provider at the receiving and he only
gonna see some encrypted packet he's
supposed to store for Bob but he doesn't
know whether it's a real message from
someone or it's for example a look
packet coming back to Bob so you
describe the providers very well and the
role in the network in terms of the
trust we still have this security the
security level of the providers
confusion by ensuring that they cannot
tell exactly how many packets you're
sending and receiving
well okay what a great answer uh before
I continue with my questions does anyone
else have a question they'd like to ask
I don't want to hog the time here I'd
like just two questions the first would
be Ania would you consider Lou Peaks to
be the state of the art of anonymous
communications so if you had asked me
this question around a year ago I would
say yes however now I'm actually working
as a head of research for new
technologies which adopted loop X as
their core mix network design and then
technologies for those of you who never
heard about it which it's very probable
because it very it's a very very new
startup it's a company which is building
a privacy network for multi purpose and
it's building actually a mixed network
based on low picks with this difference
that Lou picks when we designed it at
UCL it was designed for messaging for
email or instant messaging queries name
is building exactly the same mix that
word but with additional features which
allowed to use it for multi purposes so
messaging petitions realized VPN
cryptocurrencies and so on so it's not
anymore just a state-of-the-art is in
actual deployment thank you my question
my other question would be so it's bit
surface in Vasavi right now we are using
tor and you know for mixing we have a
huge button after that well most of the
tour packages are going very fast like
in a couple of seconds but sometimes
some peer or actually quite often some
peer is quietly so the latency sometimes
is actually two minutes and around a
phase of of asabi Cohen joined round
to always wait for the the slowest beer
and and often we don't because the
slowest beer cannot be distinguished
from a malicious denial of service
attack our so anyway the point is that
we have an anonymity Network bottleneck
there it's not our worst bottleneck but
as we are progressing to get better and
better it's going to be more and more
apparent that it slows down things and
what I realized is that you know we
don't need receiver anonymity everyone
knows that the receiver is the wasabi
bullet coordinator so if you would have
to be at an anonymity system that
actually does not require receiver
anonymity how would you go about that
would you go with some completely
different design or would you start with
low Peaks mean or mean just to take away
things from so actually you don't have
to reinvent and you look picture and you
mix Network actually what names is
building is mixed network which allows
the sender to anonymously communicate
with certain service providers which
they might be a known one so it can be
like a Bitcoin broadcasting note or it
might be a wasabi wallet or something so
it can easily use this design to build a
system without there is very limited
because if you would take the wasabi
wallet and you would plug this into them
you can do it in a way that the sender
is they know where you are they know who
you are and they want to communicate
with you but they would like to remain
anonymous visa be their wasabi wallet so
you can simply use the current design
and you don't really need to do any
changes because in loop its design if
your gonna notice that the sender when
he is sending the message to the
receiver he needs to know also the
receivers IP address
of course there are some way around it
if you don't want the sender to know
exactly the the receivers address you
can do something like you know an on
your address something similar but in
order to encrypt and to end into onion
packet your message you need to know to
whom you're encrypting it you need to
know where this packet will go so the
loop eggs already has this thing that
you need to know to whom you are sending
the message and actually the Finke which
we didn't cover in the paper is how to
deal in the situation when the receiver
is hiding his IP address and would like
to stay anonymous Visa Visa Center
whereas in the case right now as the
system was presented the receiver is
known to the center's so in terms of the
wasabi wallet at name you just plug plug
the wasabi wallet into them as the
service provider and the people who want
to use you they can very easily access
you but in an anonymous way so they're
not gonna reveal who they are all right
thank you it was a theoretical question
are rebuilding unanimity system is not
not an easy job yeah yeah definitely not
in fact even for wasabi I was working
because we are working on dotnet you
know that Microsoft stuff and it was
Windows only but it it started open
sourcing a cross-platform and we
actually did not have an anonymity at
all library for the cross-platform and
open source of net which is Cod so I had
to rebuild it and it took me like four
months yeah - before even start to work
on yeah that's true it's the building
this type of anonymous communication
system is it's not an easy thing and as
long as we can use some existing tools
it's great it's always worth to improve
them and you know design you want but
it's it's good to find a way around the
system which we have instead of like
reinventing for every single
a different system yeah I have to keep
people eyes open though yeah that's true
get back to Aviv what do you have
sorry I'm replying to my my boss same
time yep still have a job so I was just
more curious about let's see well what
am I just a question and I'll get back
to you
more questions gonna say may I quickly
just ask we can run or be a provider or
a mixer yes sir mixed nuts I the mix no
sorry that's a silly explanation mix
nuts all right and anyone can run the
mix note so it's like you can think
about them like totally so tolerate I
say run volunteers in name or in low
picks before because of that anyone can
run a mix lot would like to contribute
to the network however these are not
volunteers anymore there were there is
like a incentive model so the note
operators who will be rewarded in terms
of the providers the providers are
people who gonna you know provide you
some service I mean some service to the
client so it can be like a messaging
provider like signal for example it can
be a some provider for decentralized VPL
it can be a Bitcoin note or a
cryptocurrency exchange so whoever
delivers a service to the clients can be
an improviser so the providers are you
know the denotes providing some some
service whereas notes it can be anyone
who has equipment it would like to
contribute
what's the analogy there the providers
of its analogy was that it's like the
thorax even so so that the analogy
during the presentation was completely
perfect you could think about in
because the providers well a little bit
like the entry and exit note with this
addition that the providers could store
messages on behalf of the clients and
the clients are offline so then the the
you know import once you open the
circuit it has to be like online all the
time and using it otherwise you're gonna
start losing the packets here in low
Peaks the providers for giving you this
opportunity that you might simply go up
front and then you were coming back and
they provide restoring the incoming
packets for you in them if we change a
little bit this design with the
providers that the providers on the side
side of the center's how you can think
about that are now called mix cards and
they are checking whether you have a
credential to enter the network whereas
the providers on the recipient sites are
the providers providing some service so
these are not anymore just messaging
providers which gonna store a message on
behalf of you it might be a provider
like that obviously but there might be
also other providers like a Bitcoin note
which gonna approach cash transaction
into the network or it can be an
exchange and so on so it's not in them
the providers are especially the service
provider are not any more like an exit
note these are more like a VPN provider
now I could maybe you did a great job on
you and then the presentation by Aviv
was also wonderful so I can step in and
explain a little bit some of the
thinking and I think I might be useful
with you guys as you're you know a
Bitcoin specialist the Deep Diver bit if
we've got if we got this right so I
think one thing remember which is a huge
difference between tour and loop extend
them and mix that was in general is that
mix networks you know mix each packet
separately right so tour kind of opens
up a circuit and then stuff streams over
the circuit that's a pretty big
difference and that leads they've got
different kinds of use cases in
cryptocurrencies you think about them
you know with Bitcoin it's a you know
tcp/ip based packets but they're not
really streaming as such so they're
amendable be treating us treated as
messages we believe but then what would
be you know the service provider or the
other end which the users talking to you
know it could be you know a crypto
currency exchange and the simplest
possible level it would it could just be
literally a broadcast mixin so you know
your your your usage of NIM would be
disguised among all the other people
using them and then so you couldn't link
the fact that you sent a particular
packet to a particular broadcast and
then the time delays would alter Kate
you know the timing and metadata on the
broadcast and then that broadcast node
that Surfrider's usually be sort of an
exit node that then does the broadcast
to the rest of the Bitcoin network so
there would be a little bit latency
injected there but you would get a we
believe at least superior enough privacy
in the network level to make that
worthwhile does that make sense how
we're kind of imagining putting together
Bitcoin and and NIM and we've had an
original we people have got demos of
this working not I think I think a mere
talkie has one with Bitcoin I think he
also is with nimble humble and I think
there may be a Z cash one somewhere
maybe even in a theory in one on a on an
older version of the code base called
Katz and post so yeah I don't notice
that does that make sense yeah I
understand so if I'm the node that is
serving the blockchain data like like a
server then I would have to be also a
provider and the clients would have to
connect to different providers than me
and access me through the mix network is
that correct
so the you through the mix network yes
the only thing is that now the clients
they don't go through any provider they
go in them
they go you can think about this almost
and like directly into the mix Network
so there's no this layer of and three
providers and bye-bye would they need to
connect providers well because there has
to be some service that interfaces the
mix net to the rest of the non mix net
reality right so even that provider is
just for example tcp/ip connection you
know a certain point if you want to
touch something which isn't native then
mix that so it's like tor hidden
services there from native to tor right
you don't leave the Tor network on
another level with surf providers and
them and in loop X you know you can drop
messages off of them store them and
retrieve them later they don't really
leave the mixed network to you pull and
retrieve the message but what bitcoin
you're not really polling to retrieve
the message you just need to check the
blockchain to see if your message got
through so you would just sort of send
the message directly through that makes
that work deposit it at a service
provider they would broadcast that
message which would be an anonymous who
sent it to them and then that would
didn't be picked up by the rest of the
Bitcoin network all right thank you guys
coming with your questions because I'm
just gonna use up all my time I was
interested about incentive model of
these mixer mixer nots can you tell me a
little bit more about them yeah sure how
they do and to cover that do you want me
to explain I didn't give it a quick shot
of anything correct me if I get anything
wrong I think you should explain though
the malicious your work you did on
malicious no discovery even though it's
a different model because I think
malicious knows or something so I think
one of the issues with Lu picks is it is
I think the most cutting edge design but
you essentially still you just kind of
assume you have this mix that right so
you're assuming that you assume the
nodes are in layers and everyone's just
kind of you know you can assume a lot of
them and malicious you can detect
malicious behavior
but you still go surrogates answer the
question of how did you get you know how
did you get how did a random people the
Internet donate machines and then got
using the mixed net right so people you
could just say you just volunteer and as
soon as you volunteer we add you and
that's actually what the current test
net does so if you download I just saw
the link but if you download that rest
Network and you set up a mix node you
know it just throws you on basically so
we're not doing you know if there's no
incentive structure set up in the
current test that we haven't quite got
to that level that point in the coding
yet um and and nodes are kind of added
randomly but we don't have all the cool
vrf stuff that we need to really
guarantee that randomness is correct and
fair but if you think about it what we
really want to do if we could if we take
inspiration for bitcoins you know what
is a kind of proof of work and actually
that this concept came to me actually
Adam back who invented proof of work pre
Bitcoin he was a invited speaker at one
of these academic conferences and yeah
we're talking about Bitcoin I said well
what is it that you think you know what
would be really cool we could different
privacy angle in Bitcoin and he brought
this really good point he said you know
he said the problem it's like one be
cool of all these computational cycles
miners we're doing we're doing some kind
of privacy enhanced computation so if
you take that intuition you say well you
know you you can imagine mixing being a
useful kind of work so you should do
some sort of proof of mixing to
basically prove that that the mixer is
actually mixing correctly and so you can
imagine in a very broad strokes you can
sample network paths fairly you since
Fink's packets bit like the loop packets
through the network and you see if if
those packets got through and if those
packets to get through you can sort of
objectively judge if someone has been
delivering packets and somehow give them
some sort of reward or incentive for
doing so and the more packets you
correctly deliver then you have to
basically you know ideally get more
rewards just as
you mind more you have a chance to get
any more Bitcoin and and at some point
the other thing which I think is not in
the loop expand which also not implement
yet in them but definitely folks are
thinking about is how to deal with like
for example issues like network
congestion what if there's too many
people trying send transactions without
a mix nodes how can we expand the mix
nodes you know can we do something like
transaction fees to get more nodes
involved to deal with high amounts of
traffic the inverse what if there is
less traffic how do you maybe say okay
guys we didn't really have enough people
now and then the last question which is
how do you ensure that the people are
signed to the layers properly so let's
say I got you know one giant node and a
bunch of smaller nodes you know there's
a certain smaller nodes I can't lead to
certain you know if one layer has a much
smaller capacity at least the soroban
capacity issues for the whole network so
yeah so those are all pretty hard
questions we're trying to work through
the malabon you want to update those
yeah I'm gonna follow up a little bit on
this reward because I think your
question was more precise like how this
can work so as how I said the mixed nuts
have to do one job actually they have to
mix the traffic and forward it so how
our reward scheme works is that when the
mix nodes are joining the network they
will be questioned on how well they are
doing their job and we have this
so-called proof of mixing so what we're
gonna do is every mix node joining the
network will declare a center bandwidth
which they're willing to volunteer into
the network so they gonna declare some
throughput which they're promising and
we have a way and this actually is based
on my previous work also to see whether
they're actually fulfilling this promise
so whether they're are mixing and
processing as many packets and they
promise to do this is to ensure that
malicious mix notes which gonna join the
network which probably cannot happen
because it's a open source project and
everyone can run a node they not gonna
drop the packets they're not gonna
try to you know add more delays that
they were asked to add so they not gonna
try to no sake the mixing or to the
mixing in a different way that they are
supposed to do and based on that we will
be verifying how honestly they act and
the honest mix notes will be rewarded
and this honest mix note will have their
stake / because every mix no joining the
network will be able to stake some money
so will be just simply measuring in an
anonymous way whether the mixed note is
really behaving honestly or not and if
you are gas interested how this can be
done how we can spot malicious mix notes
I can give you a link to like a work
from the last year USENIX which we've
published which is exactly about this
how you can detect malicious will be
having mixed note and our proof of
mixing is partially based on that it's
obviously much more extended but the
idea is that we're just making sure that
the mix note are really keeping the
promise of processing this particle
traffic and they're not trying to cheat
by processing less traffic or by
processing it in a dishonest way that
could actually be put into wasabi not
not into wasabi but some kind of thing
could be figured out how to it's pretty
easy to check if if there is a civil
attack or yeah there is a CB lotta but
no one is checking because just no one
cares that much so maybe for the
next-generation mixing technology we
should figure it out that okay this is
how you can check and this is what you
want to verify or look for yeah that's a
good idea yeah I mean could you guys
explain how you guys I mean if I'm the
car horn with wasabi how do you manage
who joins the coin jointer on do you
have any so I mean
I guess you don't yes what we'll do is
we let anyone queue their coin long as
they prove that they are in possession
of their coins and that we can verify
the coins have confirmed if they are not
cooperative and they don't sign the
final transaction then they're put on a
temporary ban list so they're not able
to participate so that's how we prevent
someone who is trying to disrupt the the
mixing by not following through the
protocol the same ideas yours that they
have to put down money in order to
request for participating and if they
are if they they don't follow up with
the protocol then the militias input
gets gets banned and also children of
those inputs and orange I don't know
there are some you know you are walking
on the Bitcoin graph up and down but
generally we did not notice anyone doing
any denial of service attack yet which
I'm pretty sad because I think I figured
that out pretty well yeah this this
brings one question to me again how many
participants is in these different like
this orange yellow and green layer yeah
so actually I wanted to follow up on
that when I saw the presentation and I
forgot so one thing which I wanted to
add is we pick the those stratas those
layers which in anonymous communication
literature is called the stratified
topology but for a very good reason
because the stratified topology allows
us to horizontally scale the network
which means
we're gonna start getting more and more
traffic we can just simply add more and
more notes now the rule is the larger is
your lair I mean the more mixers are in
a single layer the more scalable is your
network in the sense the more packets
you can process because as a we've set
each packet is picking one node from
each layer randomly and that's how the
puff is built the longer the network so
the more layers we're gonna add the more
anonymity we will get however I already
did some like early evaluations and I
think three layers is a really good
sorry I'm hearing myself
someone's someone's paper you have to
mute yourself
let me just sorry okay yeah sorry for
that and so what I was saying oh yeah so
I did some early evaluations and the
free layers same a completely fine for a
very strong anonymity so the question is
only how many makes notes pay layer we
need and this depends on how much
traffic we're getting because this
allows us to scale the network right now
we're I don't remember to be honest how
many mix-ins we have I can actually see
in our test that we have three layers
and per layer we have around four to
five mix nodes but this is just a test
net so it doesn't like it's not yet
optimized for like any great throughput
or anything is just to see whether
everything is running and one more
question is that what kind of easter
snake and the minimum of it I mean I was
just thinking about sibling like getting
yourself many different nodes on the
same Strad what did you call that let's
say for the for the orange layer
I mean how what what manages or
distributes these different nodes into
different layers
what do the notes decides in which one
today go or yes so right now there is
not any distributing algorithm note any
smart algorithm I think right now
actually either people are deciding on
their own or we just assigned them a
layer but this is just right now in a
long term what we aim for is when you're
arranging those layers you have to take
into consideration a couple of things so
one is the bandwidth which the mix node
is offering because it has to be nicely
distributed we don't want to put all the
big nodes in one layer and then all the
small one small ones in a second layer
because you'll have a giant network
congestion at some point another thing
is how you say it in English like the
district in which the node is like in
which country jurisdiction that's how
you say it so we don't
so we want to nicely also distribute the
jurisdictions to make sure that the path
which you're picking per packet is as
distributed as possible another thing
which which probably we're gonna take
into consideration is also who is
running this node so probably we also
want to make sure that the path is not
composed of the nodes run by exactly the
same people so we're gonna take all of
that into consideration when we're gonna
design our algorithm and Omni assigns
you into a layer but right now we just
assign it like as we like it there's
nothing deployed yet thank you I like to
ask something about maybe this may be
something interesting for Bitcoin people
that you know the Lightning Network is
famously using the heating's as far as I
understand Spinks is unimproved Anyang
routing protocol and yes you are also
using Fink's package format so yeah
right could you explain what's spin
scope does it converts to looping
why would you do business
yes package format yes so it's it's not
likes pink things compares to low picks
on to name things it's a cryptographic
packet format so it's like a total that
they can protocol which you're gonna use
to onion encrypt your packets so loop X
we said I think in the paper or for sure
we use that in the implementation was
using Sphinx to onion encrypt the
packets and the same thing is done by
name so every packet injected into the
mixed network is onion encrypted using
the Sphinx cryptographic packet format
so you know for onion encryption you can
use some a yes if you like or you can
use things and things Bray brings a lot
of features one is that it's probably
secure the other is that it's very
compact and quite efficient actually as
given that you have to do many
cryptographic operations so name ended
is using the Sphinx packet format as the
Lightning Network and actually if you
want guys I wrote like two blog posts
for name for medium about Sphinx I can
drop your hair the links if you want to
read precisely about the features which
things is giving you that would be nice
thank you
there's a great thing about Sphinx which
is because the packets are unlink able
you know I go back to your earlier
question the question is how can ID
anonymized traffic synthetics network
and it's really hard the only way to do
it is you have to control the entire
path a single honest mix in your path is
enough to keep essentially your traffic
secure so on some level the security
characteristics of a mixed network at
least are actually quite high compared
to you know it's it's not just like oh I
need a majority to be honest actually
you know as long as there's one honest
mix and you
he's not dropping all and your traffic
isn't being dropped they your traffic
should basically be secured against you
know powerful enemies including
corrupted and malicious nodes
[Music]
thank you another implementation
question I quote to provide maximum
flexibility weeks only guarantees
unreliable datagram transmission and is
carried over UDP reliable transport is
left to the application as yes yes this
is this is actually already solved by
name because indeed in the low Peaks
paper as we discussed earlier the loop
expand work paper was state-of-the-art
design and many real-life questions I
did not go over there but at name were
actually covering that so correct me
hurry if I'm wrong but if I good
remembered the connections between mix
notes are now TCP and we also have
anonymous end-to-end acknowledgments
using the single-use reply blocks from
the Sphinx packet format and I don't
want to go into details because it's a
lot of like cryptographic details but in
general we implement that for every
packet which were sending the service
provider can send you an acknowledgement
acknowledging that he received your
packet without knowing you so still your
anonymity as the sender is fully secured
but yet we are able to send the
acknowledgement so we have this
end-to-end reliability
covert so I let me try to explain
because it is I'm trying to avoid the
cryptographic details but just to get
people the the intuition of the Serb so
yes them did add on tcp/ip and a lot of
effort is going to optimizing it you'd
have to ask Deaver Andrew about details
of that but it does work the second
question and that's important because
you know Bitcoin
uses tcp/ip and you know tor and just
lay enough does not actually cover UDP
traffic so
it's it's it's pretty hard to do
something like BitTorrent
over tour because BitTorrent UDP um okay
but interesting part about Serbs is this
can I get an acknowledgement that my
traffic came through well for some kinds
of traffic you don't need that for
example you know cryptocurrency traffic
to be honest if you're doing something
that is eventually recorded on chain
that's I'm sending a Z cash transaction
to mix that at some point you can just
check the chain if you you know that
being said there are lots of use cases
where you want an acknowledgment and the
way to think about that is that rather
than sending a message all the way back
to you so then they the they would know
who you are you and you send the message
you send essentially a sort of drop box
a little a little a sort of uh what's a
term for it Anya and Serbs you basically
drop off your message at another mix
node and that message is picked up by
the by you later so you don't have your
return address you have a place that you
know about and then later you can check
it because from the Macan retrieve that
and because the messages are the Sphynx
packets are anonymous as if i'm a mix
note i can't tell the difference between
a loop traffic versus cover traffic
versus traffic to test proof of mixing
to me it just all looks the same that
they're unlink Abul and they're being
sent you know around using this poisson
process I think that that offered you
because you can't distinguish these
kinds of traffic it offers a very high
level security and lets you do these
neat tricks lots such as serves as well
yeah in the white paper we call this
Dropbox the online the recipient
prophecy yeah which is maybe not
intuitively obvious online receiver
proxy or I don't know what we should
call it I mean hidden service sounds
pretty cool we don't to get people from
the Tor space confused because it's
really like it's like it's almost like
you had a hidden service but each time
you check it it's moving so you're
dropping off a message and that message
it says over the next message pick me up
at this location and then pick up at
that other location and so it's not
constantly going back to the same
location
yeah I'm not sure what to call them yeah
I will keep online receiver proxy to a
better name is thought up yeah but they
in general the question which you asked
about them the array ability is a very
good question because this was a bit
which was completely missing in the
Olympics design whereas in them we have
like already you know well-designed
solution for that just to advertise a
bit we are really looking for people to
run test nodes to give us feedback we
have a key base channel which you can
join just message us and it becomes
public I believe tomorrow and then that
knit that second like NIM Tech slash
dogs if you click one or two buttons for
there's got some nice intuitive
descriptions what you guys already more
advanced than most people so you don't
really need to read those but they are
kind of nice I think
nicely written but not very academic
descriptions of what's going on but
their basic they're accurate and then
most importantly there's a page called
like mix that slash installation or if
you have a Linux VM or if you're feeling
dangerous something else lying around
you know you can just install a mix node
and you'll join the network and you
won't get any rewards because that's not
worked out fully yet but you will ship
some test traffic around and we'd love
to know if that works for you and if you
have any issues installing it or issues
that you know there's all sorts of
things we may not understand in our and
our current with our current test net I
even opened a pool request Congrats you
might don't get your hopes up by just
studying your package that that wasn't
actually yeah just is there's a feedback
I was on Windows and I used
windows subsystem for Linux which is a
butyl Ubuntu into Windows so so it
worked there so so that's nice and I was
actually pretty impressed or on the mean
docks it's it was us and the docks was
up to date and quite clear and also the
software that I played around with a lot
of beta software in my life and this
thing did not give me trouble so that's
a very clear sign so keep up the work
guys thank you that's so nice to hear
that let me see there is one more
interested in this better you have all
you eated blue Peaks based on oh no a
framework for analyzing Ghana Nima's
communication protocols I did not look
into it could you could you tell me a
few things about this framework it seems
interesting yes Aloha is the framework I
mean I don't know actually how you
understood this and Noah is a research
paper a very good one
which in a very terrific way defines or
anonymity properties which I anonymous
communication system can give you so
it's not like a framework in the sense
like something implemented it's rather
like a set of definitions which if you
can fulfill them then your system is
anonymous if you want I can drop you the
link to the paper if I will quickly find
it it's actually a very nice one okay so
yes it's not like a plug-in or anything
it's rather like a set of definitions
which we cover it and which we use to
define our you know security goals which
we want to have in Olympics because it's
very nicely aggregates or their
anonymity properties which are truly
anonymous system should have know if
he's I forget if he still UCL or not but
of
sebastian still around I mean I think
that would be a really good paper to
have people read it's pretty difficult
because it's formally defining some
stuff so maybe looking at the fights men
anonyme definition paper first might be
better but it's definitely a I think is
probably the most advanced framework or
though there's the Cristian Kuhn stuff
is also quite good on privacy notions
but I think in Noah in terms of like
actually comparing different systems is
probably I think the most systematic
attempt to compare it's a it's a indeed
very very good very very good paper it's
the best and it's not that you see
anymore sadly he is working as a
researcher for visa in some around San
Francisco might be a bit busy
yeah but he's always very came to reply
email so if you guys have any questions
just drop him a line I think that would
be a great topic for a later of a
sublease research cup that sounds
interesting all the way I will I will
try to get the direction of the research
cup into into something else but but I
will I will say that later ok I have you
know what change yeah there they came up
but maybe a summary would be nice that
what changes did you have you mean come
to to you fix the main change is it's
more of extensions than a change so we
sort of say how can we add new nodes how
can we deal with capacity issues some
features that we left that were left out
of loop X that just serves or now in the
mix with these online receivers we
mentioned earlier and most most
importantly how can we generalize loop
picks to handle different kinds
applications different kinds of traffic
but still build the largest possible
enemy set from all of them is that Anya
I'm sure lots of been left
yeah but I think asked her I said very
nicely name is not like a different
design it's rather the extension of
looping so it takes to look like sand
from a strictly messaging focus mix
network it makes it general-purpose
makes network it solves many open
questions which we had in Lopes rig in
regards to availability the incentives
model the management of covered traffic
how much traffic we should pump into the
network and so on and so on so so name
actually like makes blue pigs better in
the sense it solves many research
questions which were left after the
piper was published but it's a
continuation of this work thank you I
may write to c-sharp client at some
point in my life if you guys are also
playing the long game and that that's
almost all for me I will have one more
question but that's something that's
leading to another topic I well I just
add one thing I mean I think I think
what would be really amazing for us
something we haven't looked into too
deeply is you know we have very few
people we are lots of people running mix
nodes and I'm starting to run mix nodes
that's increasing and that's great and
we need that but what would be really
useful though it's a bit of work and a
bit painful would be someone that has an
existing application the sort of say
what would it take to integrate to use
them where we're using tor today so I'm
to be very wasabi kind of question like
would it be possible that the to plug
into them and how hard is that and how
much work just but but might be a bunch
of stuff that wasabi needs or other apps
need that we don't know about and we to
be honest we only have like one or two
we don't have that many apps currently
running we just have some testing apps
like client chat program we have some
developers working on apps well all
these people are building apps from
scratch and to be really useful to see
you know like with an existing with an
existing app what it would take to
integrate
that's that's a huge interest of mine
that's very good topic and and by not
let's walk through it on the server side
but we are doing right now with Taurus
that we have a ESB dotnet application
that is that is serving HTTP requests
and through a reverse proxy through
nginx be connect tor so so so as far as
I understand I would have to run a meme
what's the name mean provider maybe that
that somehow routes my internet traffic
to the actual software is that possible
is that correct I'm not sure what I
understood correctly would you describe
what you would have to do is in order to
like you would have to run a provider
which has like an named plug-in and it
has your service which you want to
deliver and then internally within your
machine they can you know communicate
with each other but there's no like
network routing between the the part of
like the name enabling provider and and
what the service which you're running so
it can be on one machine it's just you
need like a name plug-in to to
communicate between the name and your
service okay let me try it again what I
do be torn right now is that I give door
I start tour and I gift or a port where
it forwards or the traffic and on that
port
I am listening corn with my own
application
and replying to tour with the with
whatever thing is coming to me
so it's basically a proxy is that
something like that is possible
I've I think yes I think the best person
to answer that question will be probably
Dave I really don't want to like mess up
something but what you said sounds like
probably what would be done with name as
well like you would have to work your
way around them in the same exact way as
with torpid put a pinch of salt of what
I'm just saying just to make sure you
know I'm not like I can ask Dave I will
I will you know lead developer and come
back to you but I think this sounds what
you said sounds like how it would work
sorry I don't know maybe you have a
comment about that it should be the
easier part the the server side that's
the just they just something that is
listening yeah the more difficult part
is the client side which might not be
that difficult for us but for other
applications is it is very difficult
because at least bit tour that tour does
not translate HTTP traffic because there
is a lot of problems with HTTP right
that you cannot have space in the wrong
wrong place with the header or things
like that anyway but but yeah all the
applications are using the exact same
software and an eye-roll - yeah I I
wrote the HTTP protocol from scratch
that's just interesting anyway so I
connect to your demon on the client side
and your daemon can forward it to the
server whatever I'm sending to it is
that it should be to beat
actually I think I think the client-side
integration might be quite might be
easier than any server-side stuff
because the client integration is is
built to work very similarly to how tor
works basically daemon it's running a
port it's you just throw tcp/ip traffic
at it which could include HTTP or
whatever the main thing is you some have
to retrieve those messages and do
something with them and that requires
the server side at least interfacing
pulling messages from what we currently
call if you look at the software that's
at least documents called the sfw
provider which basically means
store-and-forward providers so it holds
messages and you pull them and you can
take them out and you have messages
basically that had been anonymized but
that's on the server side the client
side you just throw stuff in the daemon
I'm running on a port mm-hmm so I think
the client side might actually be pretty
easy if you've got our if your I got tor
working it would just be another library
someone would have to put on their
device the the server-side stuff with
coin joint it would require some
thinking to be honest but I'm pretty
sure I mean it should be possible as
long as you can think of your protocols
a step of message passing sequences I
mean on the client side are you using
this folks five like yeah I believe so
okay okay maybe it's really just a few
days of plugin I think it's pretty
straight for in the client but I don't
think it's gonna be plug-and-play as the
server to be honest I think it's going
to acting the server side is the easy
part
okay well that'd be great that was yeah
because that's the part to be honest I'm
worried about but um we can put you in
the dev channel and I know there's a two
or three other people working on Bitcoin
and them and I'm sure you know I think
it's definitely an interest to us but
you know where everyone's overloaded
just trying to get the software and
there are any questions solved but
definitely like I'm sure you know folks
would like to chat about bad and could
provide pointers for stuff ever I got
kind of working on top
so we are overloaded but anyway guys
come on with your questions because I
want to keep my last question for order
and being I think I missed a very basic
part of it for how how users address
each other I mean so to my understanding
each user knows provider address for for
like for recipient of the message right
and then recipient needs to know address
provider for for sender to reply back
right or missing something I mean if
that's true then they think they know
each other so it's not immediate so I
guess I'm missing something
yeah yeah so here you have two solution
of course the recipient who wants to
reply to the center it comes in the use
case like messaging so in the case if
the center and the sender doesn't want
to reveal his identity to the recipient
that would still like to receive some
replies back to from the recipient what
we use are the single-use reply blocks
from Sphinx so it's exactly the same
technology which we use for the
acknowledgments but the single-use reply
blogs allow you to also as the recipient
add some payload layer encrypted and
then send it back to the sender without
knowing who the sender is or without
knowing the IP address of the sender so
this is how the anonymous replies are
handled oh of course it can be also the
case that the sender and recipient they
know each other they want to communicate
over the mix at all to hide the fact
that they're communicating but then you
don't need the anonymous replies but in
the case when you want to ensure that
the sender stays anonymous all the time
even in the case when
it's an active communication with
replies coming back we're using the
single use reply blocks for that so you
find this incorrectly so Sandra
increased the the paths for apply and
and it's inside this original message
right so exactly and he keep that the
sender when he pretty sorry prefers his
message to send it via the mix at work
next to the payload he also puts this
single use reply block which as you said
has prepared and pre encrypted the path
which the reply should use coming back
to him okay thank you alright it feels
like a very special question that you
left it for the last moment yeah I found
something interesting in the mean talks
actually nothing not in the loop is but
this is very pretty much what we wants
to do it it was sub in the future and
and let me just read it typically this
happens by transferring a coin to an
address then creating a privacy in
hinged coconut credential which propene
probably represents the input amount the
credential can be spent on Oni Mosley as
if it were the original value double
spending protections apply to credential
to the credential so it can only be
spent once in validators can then unlock
the volume so it can be redeemed by the
party holding the anonymized credential
any of you can can expand on this this
Bitcoin mixing logic here I don't know
if you guys are familiar with but I just
read it so if you want I can order you
give this all on you and then I think
this is a long this is actually probably
an hour conversation by itself so yeah
that's true so the name credentials are
the so called selective disclosure
credential it means that you can get an
credential confirming some statements
like proving something without ravinok
many information about yourself so for
example imagine that for whatever reason
the mixed network allows only people
above 18 years old to access it okay so
this credential you you you are able to
thanks to the validators name get a
credential which gonna prove that you're
older than 18 years old without the need
to actually say how old are you without
the need to reveal any other information
about yourself and this credential can
be for example use as a token which
allows you to enter the network so the
mix cards which i've mentioned somewhere
between the lines are like the entry
points for the pneumix network and you
can show them this credential and you're
gonna prove that you have access into
the network and now this axis can be
that for example you subscribe to a
certain service provider and for a month
you are allowed to use the service
provider so this means that you're
allowed to enter the mix network so
those credential allows you to like
anonymously prove certain statements
about yourself like either it can be
your age or it can be that you paid for
something or whatever statement it would
be without revealing sensitive
information about yourself so you can
think about this like when you want to
assign to some website you have this
like sign in with Facebook sign-in with
Google
this means that okay you can sign but
then you have to reveal a lot of
information to Facebook or Google so
this credential you can sign to
something or you can access the mixed
network without revealing all those
informations which usually are
associated with this type of tokens
blindly signed random thing this
credential is a blindly signed random
thing yes yes it is yes it's it's
blindly signed and the cryptography is
randomized well that's what gives it
some link ability properties the the
trick that it does which is quite cool
is that it's the the typical problem
like Charmian blind buying the design
stuff is you still the centralized
Authority blind like signing it
basically so coconuts kind as a
threshold signature thing so it's
decentralized you have to have acts of
in validators online to check to see if
the signatures valid and then prove
whatever so I mean it uses them in a few
different ways as you know credentials
essentially access the network to to
show that you know you're not just you
know you you're not just spamming us
you've done whatever it is that you need
to do and there's unlinked able so we
can't tell who's doing what but we just
know that everyone who has that
credential
has done whatever they need to do to
access the service provider correctly
now the real interesting question which
think we haven't really explored in them
which I suspect is where you're going
with this is how to use this kind of
scheme in terms of cryptocurrencies so
there's a paper we maybe this could also
be suggested for a future wasabi
broadcasts called coconut we could
probably drag on one or two of the
authors somebody like Mustafa would
probably have time to discuss the paper
and you can see in the original paper
they said well we could use this for
example for a theory of mixing and the
the reason they said that is because
well it's pretty trivial to implement
you know they implemented on top of the
theorem and but it had some issues for
example it had the same issues that
charmonique ash had which is they don't
really have change
denominations right so there's been a
lot of Rd to fix that both from the
original authors like George Denise's
who is Libra now but also from folks
like Amir taki who probably some of you
guys know from dark holidays has been
working on fixing it and I think you
know Dave has been of course also
working on it it's a pretty interesting
scheme similar anonymous with on
occasion credential schemes have been
around for a while Adam back from block
stream had cred lib and I think there's
a few open or any questions about how to
hook it into something like Bitcoin
correctly you might need Schnoor
signatures and taproot and stuff kind of
working a bit and deployment on Bitcoin
to make it really do its magic but I
think it's possible I mean we're kind of
busy but if we're hoping that folks
explore this it would be definitely
worth it probably a whole a whole
discussion basically yeah thank you so
why I was bringing it up because I want
you on the river are great plans about
next generation of singing with sabe
yeah just just to keep you guys up to
date everyone is that initial plans
where to bring bring up a research team
from the wasabi research Club bring
together and then everyone can work on
the mix piece on on on mixing box and
where the virus doesn't let us do that
so what we figured is that we hired
cryptographer Hungarian cryptographer
who can actually come in the office and
also the originator of the idea nothing
much and three of us are going to work
on on on the next Bitcoin mixing stuff
and while it would be nice if I we could
could also participate somehow but he
seems to be working a lot
so anyway for one months we are going to
work on this mixing tech and after that
Thank You Dario and after that we are
going to publish a draft and we can all
work together on the draft and then
implement it and what may make the most
sense to work on is a very similar
credential system is that well right now
we are we are going to the we were
talking about the whole system that how
this coconut stuff is working but
another way to think about it is that
it's basically a generalization of what
wasabi is doing right now because
hassabis blinding outputs but what we
could recognize that we don't need to
blind outputs we can blind random stuff
and that get blindly signed and random
stuff we get back and the premises and
then and output registration we can
actually tell that hey I provide you
these blinded credentials and this is
what I want to beat them for example I
want zero point five point five six
seven Bitcoin to dis adresse and zero
point and the rest to this addressed so
basically I can tell I can make exact
transactions or betrayer among
transactions in coins and I think this
makes the most sense there is also the
now if Co enjoy anything cache fusion
stuff which is very promising but I
think there are way too much risks going
down on that route and the other thing
is not sock like mixing which which we
considered but the within
obsolete mixing the problem is that the
amounts are not equal and if you look at
transaction chains equal amounts give
much better anonymity because they are
benefiting from mixing on the inputs all
the time and did not suck kind of
distribution of outputs it it never
happens
so overall remixing doesn't provide
enough shock at least better much better
anonymity like with equal amounts so
that's the does the initial idea we are
going to start working on it from Monday
next week and I'd like to propose that
finally the next session we are doing
zero link so everyone get familiar with
well zero link if you heard about that I
don't know is that is that okay for you
guys sounds good so yeah he looked at
the zero life spec and I think that
that'd be great and I mean I'll just be
from my understanding from the various
folks I know looking at coconut I don't
think anyone has actually thought up so
you know you're the first about using
this kind of technique with coin joints
so congratulations oh thank you but
Maxwell wrote it in in a few lines and
everyone seems to forgot it but he
actually wrote it in 2013 we in fact in
2011 hash coin suggested in many ways
that history lesson the same thing can
go Calise firstly onion Harry it's so
great to have you this is a really
wonderful time right oh yeah good
[Music]
anyways and and Harry was we were here
last time right because I recognize your
voice I was listening to the audio it
was
it was awesome hearing from you about
the history and the the the motivation
behind the different ideas Adam I
definitely want to join for doing the
the the next upgrade to the Wasabi's
spec and I think for next week we can we
can do two things in one we can we can
talk about zero link as well as the
implementation of zero link in wasabi
and talk about tack factors and and
issues and and things like that so if
everyone's okay with that I really love
to do something that topic yeah I think
it's fine
another thing is that I'd like to
progress on these blind blind signature
stuff so it's actually very good that
you mentioned that you actually have a
paper which is called
coconut is that true that's how I could
yes it's coconut I think the full title
is coconut threshold selective
disclosure disclosure credentials but
let me double check check yeah almost as
good its threshold issue and selective
disclosure credentials with applications
to distributed Ledger's I'm gonna drop
you the link to aircraft in the chat so
yeah that's the paper thank you very
much
so I'd like to go on this this route of
these blinding and and stuff like that
like historical papers like the child
blind signature scheme from the
beginning and there are two papers in in
the Bitcoin space actually called mixed
coin and blind coin and they came out
somewhat recently 2016 ish and they seem
to be so disconnected from the actual
field yet they were coming up in in
parallel with very similar ideas that
but what the Bitcoin privacy people are
coming up so I i I'd like to interest
look into them mixed coin was joseph
pinara
and yeah yeah I mean it's I think
they're not actually like implementing
the stuff in the production so they are
on that level disconnected but I think
that there's some convergence of people
saying hey blind signatures that could
be really cool and maybe we could do
something with that it's not currently
done in Bitcoin what was the interesting
that they came up with which one was
first mix coin WA or blind coin anyway
yes so they came up with these things
which were so being very rare problems
but those problems were already solved
but what's really interesting is what
they're thinking was there and I I would
like to really know anyway thank you
guys for coming and let me let me do the
design of the end of the episode thanks
so much guys if you have any questions
about looping so more precisely about
them just feel free to send me an email
or you know get in touch with us and
we're happy to answer all the questions
thank you very much anyone has anything
else like to bring up talk about Adam
just returned just just make sure to add
me into the discussion about the
protocol upgrades I'm sorry about the
last couple of weeks yeah I've just been
busy with the whole change of the coab
in 19 but now it's pretty calm and
everyone's switched to a working remote
so it's much much nicer now alright
definitely thank you guys
like share subscribe bye bye take care
guys thank you
[Music]